Aparna Jins E

aparnajins000@gmail.com | +917593067112

LinkedIn: aparna-jins

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with almost 3 years of experience in front-end development, specializing in React.js. Adept at crafting responsive web applications, optimizing performance, and enhancing user interfaces with a focus on application security, best coding standards, and web UI design principles.

Technologies

Languages: JavaScript (ES6+), HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks Libraries: React.js, Svelte, Redux, Node.js, SCSS/SASS, Tailwind CSS

Tools Platforms: Babel, Jira, Postman, REST APIs, Git

Soft Skills: Leadership, Problem Solving, Attention to Detail, Event Management, Analytical Thinking

Experience

Software Engineer, Impelsys Pvt Ltd

October 2022 - Present

- Developed an **encrypted invoice application** that automated monthly billing for **10+ projects**, eliminating manual Excel processes and **reducing processing time by 70%**.
- Engineered a **centralized dashboard** for tracking employee and project data, reducing employee utilization by **50**%.
- Collaborated on the **Careplans application** used by **100+ doctors** to create tailored treatment plans for lifestyle diseases, improving patient **onboarding by 40%**.
- Designed a **Project Health Report tool** with **JIRA API integration**, enabling rapid evaluation of Project Health for **10+ projects**, allowing faster risk identification by **60%**.

Research and Development Intern, NIC Kochi

August 2022 - October 2022

- Contributed in **research and architectural planning** for migrating a legacy monolithic application to a scalable **microservices-based system**.
- Designed and developed a microservice project as a **proof-of-concept** to demonstrate the feasibility of the project.
- Implemented **RabbitMQ** for reliable message passing between microservices, ensuring **data consistency** and **improving system fault tolerance**.

Education

School of Engineering, CUSAT

July 2018 - June 2022

- GPA: 8.6/10
- Bachelor of Technology Computer Science

Projects

NETFLIX-GPT GITHUB

- Developed a netflix clone using React Js,Redux, and Firebase, integrating GPT-3 for AI driven recommendations and movie listing from TMDB API
- Implemented secure authentication with Firebase and used Redux for efficient State Management, displaying personalized movie descriptions based on GPT-3 input.

CRYPTO APP GITHUE

- Developed a cryptocurrency dashboard app integrating real-time crypto currency data, market exchanges, and global crypto news using **Rapid API**.
- Built intuitive and responsive user interfaces using **Ant Design** and Implemented **Redux** for efficient state management .